Guide to the Henry R. Luce Papers 1894-2004 (bulk, 1932-1967) MS 3014
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Subject Name Files, 1894-1995 (bulk 1933-1967); 205880; 30.1 Linear feet
  - Subseries V.B. Name Files B, 1910-1974 (bulk 1933-1967); 205886
    - McKee, Reverend Elmore Mcneill, 1937-1947; 220249 (Box 130, Folder 2)
      Includes a program for the reception in honor of Harry T. Burleigh at St. George's Church.
    - McKeon, Mrs. Daniel, 1953-1954; 220250 (Box 130, Folder 2)
      Includes a blank application for a Connecticut absentee ballot.
    - McKinney, Marion A., 1953; 220252 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - McKnight, Mrs. J. P., 1954-1955; 220253 (Box 130, Folder 3)
      Includes a photograph of Clare Boothe Luce talking to two unidentified men and a photo of HRL talking to one unidentified man.
    - McLaughlin, C. T., 1951-1967; 220254 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - McLean, Edward, 1943-1944; 220255 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - McMullen, R. J., 1946-1954; 220257 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - McNamara, Robert S., 1960; 220258 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - McNutt, Paul V., 1941-1950; 220259 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Medici, Giuseppe, 1954; 220260 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Meek, Samuel W. (Mr. and Mrs.), 1938-1966; 220261 (Box 130, Folder 3)
      Includes the memorandum "The United States As a Possible Market for Italian Marble" from the J. Walter Thompson Company.
    - Meloney, Mrs. William B., 1935-1943; 220262 (Box 130, Folder 4)
      Includes a brochure for the tentative program of the New York Herald Tribune Seventh Annual Forum on Current Problems.
    - Mendl, Lady, 1947-1948; 220263 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Meng, Chih (Paul), 1944-1951; 220264 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Menzies, Rt. Hon. Robert G., 1957-1964; 220265 (Box 130, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence regarding the rule of law. Correspondence from Menzies consists of copies.
    - Merz, Charles, 1941; 220266 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Mestre, Goar, 1960; 220267 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Meyer, Eugene, 1939-1944; 220268 (Box 130, Folder 4)
      Includes the speech "The Outlook for America" by Dr. Abba Hillel Silver.
    - Miller, Francis P., 1940-1941; 220269 (Box 130, Folder 4)
      Includes memoranda from Century Club meetings and correspondence regarding aid to Great Britain.
    - Miller, Gilbert, 1939-1945; 220270 (Box 130, Folder 5)
      Includes a copy of a letter from Joachim von Ribbentrop.
    - Miller, K. Palmer, 1942-1943; 220271 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Miller, N. Richard, 1953-1955; 220272 (Box 130, Folder 5)
      Includes a memorandum on agrarian reform in Lucania, Italy.
    - Miller, Richmond P., 1945-1965; 220273 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Miller, Robert, 1951; 220274 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Miller, William J., 1958-1967; 220275 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Miller, Zenos, 1936; 220276 (Box 130, Folder 5)
      Includes a hardcover memorial book with "In Memory of Zenos Ramsey Miller" on the cover with an inscription to HRL from Zenos's father and mother.
    - Millikan, Robert, 1946; 220279 (Box 131, Folder 1)
      Contains correspondence regarding India.
    - Millis, Walter, 1938; 220280 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Milner, Lady V., 1946; 220281 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Miner, Worthington, 1956; 220282 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Minniti, Raffaele, 1955; 220283 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Minola, Enrico, 1953; 220284 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Minor, Clark H., 1966; 220285 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Minotto, James, 1961; 220286 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Miraglies, Rinaldo, 1954; 220288 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Missiroli, Mario, 1953-1954; 220291 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Mitchell, John Murray, 1936; 220292 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Mondadori, Arnoldo, 1953-1961; 220293 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Monnet, Jean, 1961-1965; 220294 (Box 131, Folder 1)
      Includes the text of the Joint Declaration of the Action Committee for the United States of Europe.
    - Montague, Gilbert H., 1941-1953; 220296 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Montana, Vanni, 1954; 220297 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Monteux, Pierre, 1950; 220298 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Moore, Mrs. Leon, 1957; 220299 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Moore, Leslie Hamilton Jr., 1959; 220300 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Morandi, Luigi, 1954-1955; 220301 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Morano, Albert P., 1945-1960; 220305 (Box 131, Folder 2)
      Includes carbon copies of letters from Morano to Dean Acheson and Arthur E. Summerfield.
    - Morey, C. R., 1953; 220307 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Morgan, Jr. J. P., 1943; 220309 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Morgenthau, Jr. Henry, 1938-1947; 220313 (Box 131, Folder 2)
      Includes the pamphlet "What Are the Facts?: The Basis for the $170,000,000 United Jewish Appeal in 1947."
    - Morlion, Father Felix (folder 1 of 4), 1953; 220315 (Box 131, Folder 2)
      Includes printed materials from the International University of Social Studies.
    - Morlion, Father Felix (folder 2 of 4), 1954; 220316 (Box 131, Folder 3)
      Includes memoranda dealing with the background of the International University of Social Studies "Pro Deo" at Rome and the preparation for a mission of Italian industrial leaders to the United States, Morlion's article "Four Problems Regarding Possibilities of American Participation in Strengthening Private Enterprise in the Anti-Communist Fight in Italy," the pamphlet "Radiazioni Psichiche del Dirigente" from the Instituto di Psicologia della Direzione, and Morlion's speeches "Taxation as an Instrument for Economic Development" and "Philosophy and Public Opinion."
    - Morlion, Father Felix (folder 3 of 4), 1955; 220321 (Box 131, Folder 3)
      Includes a set of typed notes in Italian with the top line translated as "Why Has Communism Strengthened in Italy?," a "Memorandum on the Study Project 'The Philosophy and Practice of Private Enterprise in America and Italy,' " HRL's speech "The American Proposition," and brochures from the Centro Piemontese di Cooperazione nel Lavoro.
    - Morlion, Father Felix (folder 4 of 4), 1956; 220328 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Morlion, Father Felix - HRL's Speeches and Writings Project (folder 1 of 2), 1941-1962; 220325 (Box 131, Folder 4)
      Includes a memo dealing with a possible book Morlion was planning to write using HRL's speeches and writings. Contains the following Luce speeches "Business Enterprise - 20th Century U.S.A.," "The Promised Land," "The Public Philosophy and the Spirit of Geneva," "Imperfect Freedom," "Journalism and Reponsibility," "The Rule of Law and the Administration of Justice," "Challenges to the Church," "The Title Deeds of Freedom," and "The Meaning of the Rule of Law to American Foreign Policy." HRL's articles include "The Day of Wrath," "America and Armageddon," "Holmes Was Wrong," and "The Character of the Businessman."
    - Morlion, Father Felix - HRL's Speeches and Writings Project (folder 2 of 2), 1962; 220330 (Box 131, Folder 5)
      Includes an outline for the possible book under the title The Future of the American Proposition.
    - Morris, Newbold, 1941-1954; 220332 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Morrow, Mrs. Dwight, 1942; 220335 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Morton, Thruston B., 1956; 220336 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Moses, Herbert, 1948; 220337 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Mountbatten, Lord, 1946; 220338 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Mullins, C. L., 1946; 220339 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Mundt, Karl E., 1945-1950; 220342 (Box 131, Folder 5)
      Includes the press release "Member of New Unamerican Activity Group Puts Pertinent Questions to Prominent Americans."
    - Munsel, Partice, 1958; 220343 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Munson, C. S., 1936; 220344 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Murdoch, Keith, 1952-1953; 220345 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Murphy, Charles T., 1956; 220346 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Murphy, George, 1967; 220348 (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Murphy, Henry Killam, 1938; 220349 (Box 132, Folder 1)
      Includes brochures on Murphy titled "Lecturer on 'New China.' "
    - Murphy, Paul I., 1963-1964; 220350 (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Murphy, Robert D., 1959-1964; 220351 (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Murphy, Thomas F., 1951; 220352 (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Murray, J. Edward, 1965-1966; 220353 (Box 132, Folder 1)
      Includes Murray's speech "The Changing Newspaper Reader."
    - Murray, Reverend John Courtney, 1950-1966; 220354 (Box 132, Folder 1)
      Includes a carbon copy of an untitled article? about Dr. Oppenheimer and his loyalty to the United States, and page proofs for the article "Christianity in a Post-Western Era" by David Danzig.
    - Murray, Philip, 1942; 220355 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      Includes a memorandum regarding the relationship between United China Relief and the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO).
    - Murray, Thomas E., 1955; 220356 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Murrow, Edward R., 1947; 220357 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Mydans, Shelley (Mrs. Carl), 1965; 220358 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Myerberg, Michael, 1942; 220359 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Naguib, President of Egypt, 1954; 220360 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      Contains a letter of gratitude from HRL.
    - Nasser, President Gamal Abdel, 1956-1957; 220361 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      Contains copies. Includes the conclusion of an address given by HRL on the subject of world brotherhood at a dinner of the National Conference of Christians and Jews.
    - Nast, Conde, 1935-1940; 220362 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Nathan, George Jean, 1940; 220363 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Naughton, J. W., 1953; 220364 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Naumer, Helmuth, 1937; 220365 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Neave, Alexander C., 1942; 220366 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Necchi, Vittorio, 1954; 220367 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Neils, Patricia - Correspondence with Frederick Gruin Regarding the Luce China Book Project, 1983-1988; 220368 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      Correspondence dealing with Neils's project for the book under the working title of The Influence of Henry Robinson Luce on American Images, Attitudes, and Policies Toward China eventually published as China Images in the Life and Times of Henry Luce. Includes Gruin's chapter by chapter comments on the manuscript.
    - Neils, Patricia - Correspondence with Henry Luce III Regarding the Luce China Book Project, 1981-1988; 220369 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Neils, Patricia - Correspondence with Time Inc. Regarding the Luce China Book Project, 1944, 1982-1988; 220370 (Box 132, Folder 3)
      Includes copies of memoranda and correspondence from 1944 between HRL and Teddy White regarding China.
    - Neils, Patricia - Correspondence A-Z Regarding the Luce China Book Project, 1981-1988; 220371 (Box 132, Folder 3)
      Includes copies of letters from Madame Chiang Kai-shek, Clare Boothe Luce, and Theodore H. White.
    - Neils, Patricia - Miscellaneous Correspondence Regarding the Luce China Book Project, 1985; 220372 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Nelson, Donald, 1942; 220373 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Nelson, George, 1955; 220374 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Neumiller, L. B., 1950; 220375 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Nevins, Allan, 1950; 220376 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Newell, William S., 1945; 220377 (Box 132, Folder 4)
      Includes a "certificate of qualifications" awarded to HRL by the Bath Iron Works Corporation.
    - Niarchos, Stavros S., 1956-1958; 220378 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Nichols, J. Brooks, 1933; 220379 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Nichols, Ruth, 1943; 220380 (Box 132, Folder 4)
      Includes a brochure for Relief Wings Inc.
    - Nikoli, Antonio, 1953; 220381 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Netz, Marie, 1948; 220382 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Niccoli, Giovanni, 1953; 220383 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold - Rough Notes, 1943-1967; 220384 (Box 132, Folder 4)
      Contains HRL's handwritten notes on Niebuhr's book The Nature and Destiny of Man and other unidentified works.
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold - Miscellaneous, 1944-1955; 220385 (Box 132, Folder 4)
      Includes a brochure for the journal Christianity and Crisis.
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1952-1960; 220386 (Box 132, Folder 4)
      Includes a list of Pat Nixon's trips, and a carbon copy of a letter with HRL's condolences following the 1960 election. Correspondence from Nixon consists of copies.
    - Noble, Edward J., 1944; 220387 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Nolan, James, 1953; 220388 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Nomura, Kichisaburo, 1941; 220389 (Box 133, Folder 1)
      Contains an invitation to a reception in honor of Nomura.
    - Norden, Helen Brown, circa 1936-1941; 220390 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Norman, Reginald T., 1939-1940; 220391 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Norris, Charles G., 1935-1943; 220392 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Norris, Ernest E., 1944; 220393 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Norris, Frank, 1940; 220394 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Norton, B. W., 1933; 220395 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Nu, U., 1955; 220396 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Nyi, N. C., 1958-1959; 220397 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Obermer, Seymour, 1966; 220398 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Odlum, Floyd B., 1943-1960; 220399 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - O'Hara John, 1937-1944; 220400 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Olivetti, Adriano, 1953-1954; 220401 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Ollenhauer, Erich, 1953; 220402 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Ormerod, C. B., 1943-1961; 220403 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Osmena, Sergio, 1942-1944; 220404 (Box 133, Folder 1)
      Includes a press release from the Office of the Commonwealth of the Philippines with the speech "American-Filipino Partnership in Bataan."
    - O'Sullivan, J. L., 1954; 220405 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Owens, Hamilton, 1948; 220406 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Owens, Rachel W., 1933; 220407 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Oxnam, Bishop G. Bromley, 1946-1952; 220408 (Box 133, Folder 2)
      Includes a pamphlet with excerpts from Oxnam's sermon "On This Rock I Will Build My Church."
    - Pace, Jr. Frank, 1960-1965; 220409 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Pacelli, Princess Gabrielle, 1951-1953; 220410 (Box 133, Folder 2)
      Includes the memo "The Periodical Press in Italy" in Italian.
    - Packard, David, 1966; 220411 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Paepcke, Walter, 1938-1959; 220412 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Page, Arthur W., 1938-1943; 220413 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Pahlavi, Mohammad Reza (Shah of Iran), 1949; 220414 (Box 133, Folder 2)
      Contains invitations.
    - Pai, Mrs. Sang M., 1954; 220415 (Box 133, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of Sang Myung High School in Korea and Dr. and Mrs. George A. Fitch? in front of the school building and in front of a crowd of students.
    - Paik Too Chin, 1953; 220416 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Palamas, Christian X., 1956; 220417 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Pallavicini, Princess Elvina, 1955-1961; 220418 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Palma, Franco, 1955; 220419 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Paley, William S., 1937-1965; 220420 (Box 133, Folder 3)
      Includes a pamphlet with Paley's speech "The American System of Broadcasting" and a proposal for a day nursery in West Harlem, NY.
    - Palmer, Carleton H., 1933-1951; 220421 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Palmer, Reverend E. Hoyt, 1939-1944; 220422 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Palmer, Paul, 1948; 220423 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Pampaloni, Geno, 1953; 220424 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Pandit, Mrs. V. L - Dinner on 3 February 1945, 220425 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Paolozzi, Countessa Alice, 1954; 220426 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Parker, Kenneth, 1950; 220427 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Parr, Reverend L. A., 1939; 220428 (Box 133, Folder 3)
      Includes a newsletter from the First Congregational Church, Ann Arbor, MI.
    - Parsons, Harold, 1954-1955; 220429 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Pascone, Teri, 1952-1954; 220430 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Pasetti, Leandro, 1954; 220431 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Paterson, Chat, 1947; 220432 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Patterson, Howard A., 1965; 220433 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Patterson, James T., 1964-1965; 220434 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Patterson, Morehead, 1933-1965; 220435 (Box 133, Folder 4)
      Includes an annual report for the American Machine and Foundry Company, and the pamphlet "Besides ... It's Good Business."
    - Patterson, Richard C., 1942-1956; 220436 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Patterson, Robert, 1942-1952; 220437 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Patterson, Rufus L., 1937-1954; 220438 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Pawley, William, 1943-1960; 220439 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Payne, J. Dillingham, 1958-1962; 220440 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Peabody, Rt. Reverend Malcolm, 1965; 220441 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Peake, Charles, 1958; 220442 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Peale, Norman Vincent, 1950; 220443 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Pearson, Lester B., 1961; 220444 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Peilov, Assen, 1954; 220445 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Pemberton, Brock, 1937-1944; 220446 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Percy, Charles H., 1966-1967; 220447 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Perkins, Frances, 1939; 220448 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Perkins, Milo, 1943; 220449 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Perrone, Alessandro, 1953-1955; 220450 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Person, John L., 1953; 220451 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Pettus, W. B., 1941; 220452 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Pew, J. Howard, 1961-1963; 220453 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Pew, Joseph Jr., 1944; 220454 (Box 133, Folder 5)
      Contains a summary of a conversation with Pew where he describes a meeting with Herbert Hoover on the evening of 6 December 1941.
    - Peyton, Father Patrick, 1957; 220455 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Pharis, Mrs. Charles S., circa 1932-1967; 220456 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1938-1943; 220457 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Philip, Duke of Edinburgh - Dinner, 1960; 220458 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Phillips, Maria Salata, 1953; 220459 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Piccinini, Dr., 1954; 220460 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Pickford, Mary, 1945; 220461 (Box 134, Folder 1)
      Includes programs for the Carnegie Hall appearance of Arturo Toscanini and Vladimir Horowitz to benefit the National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis.
    - Piel, David, 1948; 220462 (Box 134, Folder 1)
      Includes a memo dealing with the organization and methods of operation for the company Ram Films Inc., and the first rough treatment outlines for the motion pictures "For China's Children" and "The New Midwife."
    - Pike, Bishop James A., 1964; 220463 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Pin, Hsiung, 1946; 220464 (Box 134, Folder 1)
      Includes a letter in Chinese.
    - Pine, David, 1954-1955; 220465 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Pineau, Christian, 1957; 220466 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Pirelli, Alberto, 1953-1958; 220467 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Pitkin, Walter B., 1940; 220468 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Pitman, Paul M., 1952-1964; 220469 (Box 134, Folder 2)
      Includes the paper "Four Years as a College President" by Pitman.
    - Pitts, J. W., 1957; 220470 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Pizzi, Amilcare, 1958-1961; 220471 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Pleren, Rene, 1950; 220472 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Plotkin, Rabbi Albert, 1966; 220473 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Plummer, L. A., 1933; 220474 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Poling, Dr. Daniel A., 1955-1964; 220475 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Ponti, Gio, 1954-1963; 220476 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Ponticelli, Countess Vera, 1954; 220477 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Pope, Arthur Upham, 1943-1952; 220478 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Potter, John S., 1945-1954; 220479 (Box 134, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence dealing with conditions in China, a copy of the article "Henry Luce -- One of the Men Behind the Scenes of American Imperialism" by Liu Liang-mo, and an issue of The Shanghai Letter a China market bi-weekly circulated privately to businessmen.
    - Powell, Adam Clayton, 1958-1967; 220480 (Box 134, Folder 3)
      Contains correspondence with The First Presbyterian Church of New York, and the report "The Adam Clayton Powell Case: A Test for Christian Ethics."
    - Prentice, P. I., 1947-1962; 220481 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Preston, Alice, 1949; 220482 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Price, Harry B., 1938-1946; 220483 (Box 134, Folder 3)
      Includes a script for a play? "A Christmas Pantomime," a draft of the article "A Nation Grows Up or Suffering, Sin, and Sacrifice" by Elizabeth Rugh Price, and correspondence from The American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression.
    - Pryce-Jones, Alan, 1961; 220484 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Pryor, Jr. Samuel F., 1938-1953; 220485 (Box 134, Folder 4)
      Includes a letter from Governor Dwight H. Green.
    - Pulitzer, Jr. Joseph, 1955; 220486 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Pulitzer, Ralph, 1933; 220487 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Pulliam, Eugene C., 1958-1966; 220488 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Purves, Robert O., 1955; 220489 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Pusey, Nathan, 1953-1955; 220490 (Box 134, Folder 4)
      Includes the text of an address delivered by Pusey at the opening convocation of the Harvard Divinity School.
    - Putnam, George Palmer, 1933; 220491 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Quay, James, 1948; 220492 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Quezon, President Manuel, 1941-1944; 220493 (Box 134, Folder 4)
      Contains telegrams.
    - Quintieri, Quinto, 1956; 220494 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Raffaelli, Guido, 1955; 220495 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Rager, Edward, 1941; 220496 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Ramond, Albert, 1937; 220497 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Rand, Jr. J. H., 1933; 220498 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Rankin, Karl Lott, 1953; 220499 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Rao, Paul P., 1955; 220500 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Rashid, Baddia J., 1955-1956; 220501 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Rayburn, Sam, 1949; 220502 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Read, Dr. David H. C., 1956-1967; 220503 (Box 134, Folder 5)
      Includes the text of the sermons "This Year of Grace," "Faith and the New Fatalism," and "Why the Reformation Lives and Grows" preached in the Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church in New York.
    - Redmond, Roland L., 1939; 220504 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Reece, Carroll, 1948; 220505 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Reed, Guy E., 1948-1953; 220506 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Reed, Philip D., 1948; 220507 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Reid, Ogden, 1944-1964; 220508 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Reid, Whitelaw, 1948-1952; 220509 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Reinert, Reverend Paul C., 1955; 220510 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Reiser, Professor Oliver, 1964-1966; 220511 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Reisner, Reverend Christian F., 1936-1940; 220512 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Relin, Bernard, 1952-1966; 220513 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Repplier, Theodore, 1955; 220514 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Resor, Stanley, 1938-1962; 220515 (Box 135, Folder 1)
      Includes press releases from the United Church Canvass.
    - Reynolds, Quentin, 1936; 220516 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Rhee, Syngman, 1944-1955; 220517 (Box 135, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence from Louise Yim, a press release from The Korean Commission, and an untitled essay by Rhee "regarding the sentiment of the Asiatic people after the Japanese war." Correspondence from Rhee consists of copies.
    - Rhyne, Charles S., 1959-1960; 220518 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Ribeiro, Victor, 1967; 220519 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Richards, Guy, 1945; 220520 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Richards, Ira, 1936-1939; 220521 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Richards, John, 1939; 220522 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Rickenbacker, Edward V., 1946-1951; 220523 (Box 135, Folder 1)
      Includes a sticker from Eastern Air Lines.
    - Rickover, Admiral H. G., 1960-1961; 220524 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Rieber, T., 1936-1940; 220525 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Riemer, George, 1964-1965; 220526 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Ritter, Roger E., 1937-1960; 220527 (Box 135, Folder 2)
      Includes a spiral bound notebook with copies of letters of reference, a resume with an attached photograph of Ritter, and photographs of showrooms with glass and porcelain. In addition there is a photograph of Mr. and Mrs. Ritter and the exterior view of the house they are living in.